<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 13:44:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>#PrestaShopDay: Recapping an amazing event!</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashopday-recapping-amazing-event/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashopday-recapping-amazing-event/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 13:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20165</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>We expected a large attendance at PrestaShop Day and you didn’t disappoint! More than 2,000 people joined us at Carreau du Temple and we thank you! PrestaShop Day would not have been a success without you nor the partners and experts who joined us. PrestaShop Keynote: WeCommerce is better Ecommerce It was a memorable day [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashopday-recapping-amazing-event/">#PrestaShopDay: Recapping an amazing event!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">We expected a large attendance at PrestaShop Day and you didn’t disappoint! More than 2,000 people joined us at Carreau du Temple and we thank you! PrestaShop Day would not have been a success without you nor the partners and experts who joined us.</p>
<p><span id="more-20165"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b;">PrestaShop Keynote: WeCommerce is better Ecommerce</span></h2>
<p>It was a memorable day filled with networking and discussions about a topic that unites us &#8211; eCommerce. A PrestaShop Keynote was kicked off by Bruno Leveque (PrestaShop CoFounder and CEO), Octave Klaba (Founder of OVH), Nicolas Ferrary (Country Manager France of Airbnb) and Charles Wells (PrestaShop Chief Product Officer).</p>
<p>It featured major announcements, the launch of the Integration Fund, our new <a href="https://vimeo.com/130541197" target="_blank">visual identity</a>, <a href="http://ambassadors.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">Ambassadors Program</a>, product updates, and much more! With the <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/" target="_blank">Integration Fund</a>, over $1,000,000 has been dedicated to funding localized module development all over the world.</p>
<p><strong><a title="PrestaShop Keynote &quot;WeCommerce is better e-commerce&quot; By Bruno Lévêque" href="//fr.slideshare.net/PrestaShopOfficial/keynote1-49448932" target="_blank">PrestaShop Keynote &#8220;WeCommerce is better e-commerce&#8221; By Bruno Lévêque</a></strong></p>
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;">
<p>We hope you left with great ideas and improvement projects from our workshops, audits, roundtables or conferences. Missed any presentations?<a href="http://fr.slideshare.net/PrestaShopOfficial/presentations" target="_blank"> Flip through our slides</a>!</p>
</div>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b;">Photo album</span></h2>
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;">
<p>Relive the highlights of our day on Facebook in our <a href="https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.1123256561024618.1073741861.114089955274622&amp;type=3" target="_blank">#PrestaShopDay photo album!</a></p>
</div>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b;">Official figures from PrestaShopDay</span></h2>
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;"></div>
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;">Didn’t get enough of PrestaShop day? Check out these figures :</div>
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;"></div>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/fr/files/2015/06/infography-116mb.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20193" alt="infography-11,6mb" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/infography-116mb.jpg" width="960" height="4464" /></a></p>
<h2><span style="color: #251b5b;">Thank you</span></h2>
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;">A special thank you to our sponsors, <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/payment/paypal" target="_blank">PayPal</a>,<a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/shipping/la-poste-coliposte" target="_blank"> So Colissimo</a><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/shipping/la-poste-coliposte" target="_blank">,</a> <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/marketplaces/twenga" target="_blank">Twenga Solutions</a> and<a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/industry-partners/payment/hipay" target="_blank"> HiPay</a> !</div>
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;">
<p>And our press partners <a href="http://www.maddyness.com/" target="_blank">Maddyness</a>, <a href="http://frenchweb.fr/" target="_blank">FrenchWeb.fr</a>, <a href="http://www.viuz.com/" target="_blank">Viuz</a>, <a href="http://www.widoobiz.com/" target="_blank">Widoobiz</a>, <a href="http://devmag.fr/" target="_blank">Devmag.Fr</a>, <a href="http://www.ecommercemag.fr/" target="_blank">ecommercemag.fr </a>and <a href="http://www.e-marketing.fr/" target="_blank">eMarketing.fr</a>.</p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashopday-recapping-amazing-event/">#PrestaShopDay: Recapping an amazing event!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashopday-recapping-amazing-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 6 Questions to Ask When Pricing a New Product</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-6-questions-ask-pricing-new-product/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-6-questions-ask-pricing-new-product/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 13:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20157</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Launching a new product should be more of an enlightening experiment and less of a nightmare. The difference between a flop and a smash hit can depend on factors ranging from marketing to pricing. In this article, we’ve asked Wiser content marketer, Angelica to share her advice on the pricing side of introducing a new [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-6-questions-ask-pricing-new-product/">Top 6 Questions to Ask When Pricing a New Product</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Launching a new product should be more of an enlightening experiment and less of a nightmare. The difference between a flop and a smash hit can depend on factors ranging from marketing to pricing. In this article, we’ve asked Wiser content marketer, Angelica to share her advice on the pricing side of introducing a new product to market. She’ll get you up to speed on the strategies you can implement to hit your <a href="http://blog.wiser.com/introducing-new-product-one-step-time/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=newproduct" target="_blank">new product launch</a> out of the park. </p>
<p><span id="more-20157"></span></p>
<p>It can be tricky to go about pricing a product that the market has never seen before. There are many concerns that go through a merchant’s mind, such as: will consumers find this useful? Will they think it’s priced fairly? Here are a few suggestions to help price it correctly the first time and every time after that.</p>
<h2 style="color:#d5a536">1. How are your other products priced?</h2>
<p>The new product you’re adding needs to make sense with your current assortment and overall pricing strategy. Unless of course, the idea is to test a new direction that you’re thinking about taking your store and brand in. But in general, if you have built your brand around being stylish and affordable, then your product should be priced in-line with your existing inventory. That will help it appeal to the customer base you’ve built up and reach new potential audiences. </p>
<h2 style="color:#d5a536">2. What are the substitutes for this new product?</h2>
<p>This is often a good starting place for many merchants because it provides them with an idea of the prices shoppers are already willing to pay. If you’re introducing a high-end water bottle made with a new and sustainable material that keeps beverages cold for 20 hours, see how other insulated bottles are priced. The idea here is to do a bit of competitive monitoring to find your product’s place in the market.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.wiser.com/get-smart-business-intelligence/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=newproduct" target="_blank">Competitor data</a> will be especially important as other merchants begin selling the item. Even if you have an exclusive relationship with the manufacturer, copy cats could pop up once your new product proves to be successful. Keeping up with the prices for the same and similar products as they become available should give you the information you need to keep prices competitive.  </p>
<h2 style="color:#d5a536">3. How much does the item cost to produce?</h2>
<p>The cost of production should influence your minimum price you’re willing to sell the product for. It’s important to know the cost of your product because selling below that amount means you’re losing money. Your minimum price should always be at or above cost. </p>
<h2 style="color:#d5a536">4. How elastic is the price?</h2>
<p>In other words, how much does the price of your product vary? Products that can sustain demand at a variety of prices are considered elastic. On the other hand, products with small price differences are considered inelastic. Inelastic products are easier to price because their prices don’t fluctuate much. Elastic products, however, can have prices that vary greatly based on the supplier and market conditions. </p>
<p>Because the perfect price isn&#8217;t stagnant, figuring out the “perfect price&#8221; for your new item can be difficult. It’s important to monitor how the market responds to your item at different prices. Although you can monitor your competitors’ prices manually, you can also choose to automate this process by working with a repricer. </p>
<p>Repricers come in the form of software that aggregates sales history, market and competitive intelligence, and minimum and maximum prices. They make it possible to make informed price changes in real-time. Repricers can help you efficiently price a new product by continuously updating the price to keep up with the market’s reaction to it.</p>
<h2 style="color:#d5a536">5. Is your product seasonal?</h2>
<p>Back to the example of the water bottle. Introducing it during the spring when sporty shoppers are likely to be looking for new gear for their upcoming trips could result in a higher price than if it was introduced in the middle of winter. But once seasons change, keeping the price the same probably isn’t a good call. </p>
<p>That’s where a repricer comes in again; it can reprice based on all the metrics that matter most, like traffic and conversions. If conversions drop when autumn rolls around, drop prices to bump conversions back up.</p>
<h2 style="color:#d5a536">6. How much inventory do you have?</h2>
<p>Based on how much inventory you have in stock, use pricing to prevent depleting your levels or having an overflowing warehouse. To avoid the former, increase prices when you’re low. In case of the latter, lower prices to make room for new merchandise.</p>
<h2 style="color:#d5a536">In Summary</h2>
<p>By this point you might be wondering if there is a clear-cut way to price new products. I don’t mean to disappoint, but there really isn’t. There are so many factors at play and there’s no right way to do it. I would argue that not having a concrete method is actually a good thing: it leaves the strategy up to you and gives you the ability to customize it to fit your existing brand and <a href="http://www.wiser.com/pricing-strategies?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=newproduct" target="_blank">pricing strategy</a>. </p>
<p>What strategies have you used to price new products in your shop? Share your experience and techniques in the comments below. </p>
<h2 style="color:#d5a536">About the Author</h2>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/Angelica-Valentine-BW-headshot-150x150.jpg" alt="Angelica Valentine" width="100" height="100" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-20158" /><br />
Angelica Valentine is the Content Marketing Manager at <a href="http://www.wiser.com/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=newproduct" target="_blank<br />
">Wiser</a>, the leading pricing intelligence suite. Wiser helps online retailers reprice their new and established products in real-time to optimize for revenue and profit. </p>
<p>Top Wiser features include:</p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li>Easily develop an optimized pricing strategy that can keep up with the market</li>
<li>Seamlessly integrate with PrestaShop carts</li>
<li>Gain access to in-depth analytics to prove ROI</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-6-questions-ask-pricing-new-product/">Top 6 Questions to Ask When Pricing a New Product</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-6-questions-ask-pricing-new-product/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Support your ecommerce business with social media (Part 1 of 2)</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 10:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20108</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today, we welcome Hanna Oeljeschlaeger, Social Media Coach for DACH &#38; UK at HootSuite. Knowing how complex the social media landscape can be to navigate, she’s going to share strategies e-merchants can use to identify the most effective social networks for improving web traffic and customer communication, without wasting money or time that could be [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media/">Support your ecommerce business with social media (Part 1 of 2)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="font-style:italic">Today, we welcome Hanna Oeljeschlaeger, Social Media Coach for DACH &amp; UK at HootSuite. Knowing how complex the social media landscape can be to navigate, she’s going to share strategies e-merchants can use to identify the most effective social networks for improving web traffic and customer communication, without wasting money or time that could be better spent on developing core business.</p>
<p>In less than a decade, social media has gone from being a “fancy add-on” for a Business Plan to offering an actual set of practical tools which helps ecommerce businesses connect with potential customers. Social media enables marketers to conduct in-depth research within identified target segments, create personalized messages, interact with audiences directly and react to changing market conditions in real-time. So the question is no longer whether to include social media in a business plan but how to include it.<br />
<span id="more-20108"></span></p>
<h4 style="color:#3db5d0">Cutting through the noise</h4>
<p>Your ecommerce marketspace is based on one or more virtual platforms surrounded by noise from a large number of competitors, opinion leaders and other market participants, such as bloggers, who can all influence your online image by sharing positive or negative experiences with your brand. Having a clear voice will allow you to raise brand awareness and establish a lasting positive online reputation, ensuring coherence between your corporate identity and online image. </p>
<p>But how can you achieve these goals without wasting time and resources that should focus on supporting your core business? In this post, I outline a 3-step strategy to identify the most profitable networks for your business and develop a proactive communication strategy around only the most appropriate social media outlets.</p>
<h2 style="color:#277083">1. Divide your target group into narrowly focused target segments using “Personas”</h2>
<p>First, you need a clear image of the online audience you intend to reach. Given the anonymity of the virtual marketspace, a good understanding of target group characteristics gives your message a better chance of cutting through the noise to reach the segments that interest you. Developing “<a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">personas</a>” is a proven way to illustrate characteristics, which simplifies the process of identifying specific segments within your broader target group. So how can you develop these for your business?</p>
<p>One way is to use the Twitter “search” tab of our Hootsuite dashboard, which provides an easy and effective function to set up search streams. These streams help you identify characteristics of your target group and divide it into clear-cut segments along identified demographics and psychographics. For more detailed information feel free to ask our Social Media Coaches <a href="http://ow.ly/LkUu2" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/personas-1024x550.png" alt="personas" width="700" height="375" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20109" /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;font-style:italic">Quick guide to setting up  your search streams</p>
<p>To give you an example of how search streams can support the segmentation process, let’s look at <a href="http://www.sutterhome.com/" target="_blank">Sutter Home</a>. The vineyard recently started an online business in addition to their local stores. As a first step towards this online expansion, management had to narrow its existing offline target group into smaller segments specific to their online shop. </p>
<p>In-depth research along industry keywords, including polls and monitoring of online conversations, allowed them to develop a specific persona. Research results were bundled into sections and framed by an avatar image and name within the age range of 21- 30, which corresponded to the majority of prospects within the target segment. The persona, illustrated below, focused on the most lucrative target segment within the broader target group.</p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-6 col-xs-12">
<p><strong>Online target group (blurred)</strong></p>
<p>		<img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/target-group.jpg" alt="target-group" width="800" height="532" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20110" />
	</div>
<div class="col-sm-6 col-xs-12">
<p><strong>Target segment (focused)</strong></p>
<p>		<img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/target-segment.png" alt="target-segment" width="561" height="330" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20111" />
	</div>
</div>
<p>Personas provide the basis for the next two steps: matching target segment characteristics with the most effective communication tools and message appeal. These choices determine which social media networks are most effective for your ecommerce business.</p>
<h2 style="color:#277083">2. Match your core product or service with your social media kit</h2>
<p>Once you’ve identified your key target, it’s time to identify which communication tools your ecommerce  business needs, based on your product or service’s core offer. The table below illustrates several different kinds of businesses and their core offer, with a suggested communication focus and the most effective social media channel for transmitting that message. </p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/06/tab-en.png" alt="Support your ecommerce business with social media" width="630" height="340" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20116" /></p>
<p>This selection is based on the largest global networks (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Google+, Pinterest, Instagram and Youtube), so you can use it as a guideline and adapt it to your local market. For example, are there any additional local social networks which you have to consider? E.g. Viadeo for France, Xing for Germany. </p>
<p>The ranking indicates the three most suitable social media networks for promoting your core product or service on a global scale. With the <a href="http://ow.ly/LkW6e" target="_blank">Hootsuite</a> dashboard, you can connect your social media networks to communicate coherently and simultaneously across channels, as well as monitor all activities and react to changes in the market in real time.</p>
<p style="font-style:italic;text-align:center">
	Got it so far? Great!<br />
	Let&#8217;s take a break to set up your Social Communication Strategy, while we wait for the crucial last step in the following blog post. The next post will show you how to stand out against your competitors using the right set of social media tools.<br />
	Get ready by starting your free 30-day trial: <a href="http://ow.ly/L7QJr" target="_blank">http://ow.ly/L7QJr</a>
</p>
<p>Written by Hanna Oeljeschläger (@HootHanna)<br />
Social Media Coach for DACH &amp; UK at Hootsuite</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media/">Support your ecommerce business with social media (Part 1 of 2)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop launches a $1,000,000 Integration Fund for the Community</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaux Choplin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20101</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Since its creation in 2007, PrestaShop has helped thousands of merchants achieve success through their online stores. Over the years, many new features have been added to the open source software thanks to its unique ecosystem. The latest evolution is our Cloud version, which we were proud to release earlier this year. With no hosting [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/">PrestaShop launches a $1,000,000 Integration Fund for the Community</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since its creation in 2007, PrestaShop has helped thousands of merchants achieve success through their online stores. Over the years, many new features have been added to the open source software thanks to its unique ecosystem. The latest evolution is our Cloud version, which we were proud to release earlier this year. With no hosting fees, PrestaShop Cloud allows merchants anywhere to create a store in a single click.</p>
<p>Each innovation is inspired by our desire to simplify ecommerce and make it accessible to everyone across the world. The 800,000 members of our incredible community and our shared passion for ecommerce are what make it all possible. Our success is driven by our community via the PrestaShop Addons Marketplace. This year our contributors will earn over $5,000,000 selling their modules and themes on our marketplace!</p>
<p>We want every developer to be able to give the emerchants in his or her country the power to easily achieve ecommerce success. That’s why we’re thrilled to announce the launch of a <strong>$1,000,000 Integration Fund</strong> dedicated to our community and intended to reinforce the positive relationships with developers that have contributed to our shared success.<br />
<span id="more-20101"></span></p>
<h4 style="color:#df0064">$1,000,000 to invest in our global community </h4>
<p>Using this Fund, we hope to build a catalog of local modules so that every merchant, no matter where they are, has access to the basic features necessary to run a successful eCommerce activity in his or her country (payment modules, shipping modules, modules for local marketplace connection and modules to simplify administrative procedures).</p>
<h4 style="color:#df0064">How can you get involved?</h4>
<p>It’s simple. Whether you’re a new contributor or you’ve been with us for a while, just send us your idea for a local module. </p>
<p>If your idea and skills convince us to select your project, you’ll be eligible to receive funding to cover your development costs (this amount is determined on a case-by-case basis). Once your module is developed and online on PrestaShop Addons, you’ll receive this personalized funding, as well as 30% of the revenues on your module’s sales (until the PrestaShop’s total commission on your module  reaches the amount of the awarded funding), then 70% on all following sales. </p>
<p>&#8220;I first developed a shipping solution for my uncle’s e-shop that I now sell on Addons Marketplace. I ended up selling it almost 2,000 times”, says Emmanuel M, Addons contributor. Instead of taking on the costs of a custom-made development, merchants can buy modules on Addons Marketplace and benefit from high-volume availability, reducing costs by a factor of more than 20. For developers, the Addons Marketplace offers an incredible opportunity to significantly increase revenues. The Integration Fund was created to drive module development and foster positive relationships between community members and PrestaShop. </p>
<p>Do you have an idea for your local market? </p>
<p><a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/integration-fund" target="_blank">Pitch your idea and apply for the PrestaShop Integration Fund</a></p>
<p>Stay tuned on the Integration Fund thanks to the hashtag <strong>#1million4devs</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/">PrestaShop launches a $1,000,000 Integration Fund for the Community</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>[Case Study] How to Easily Boost Conversion Rates with Personalization</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 12:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20093</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In today’s post, PrestaShop partner Nosto explains how Planet Fitness increased conversions using personalization. Did you know that for every $92 spent on acquiring visitors, less than $1 is spent on converting them into customers? The truth is, in the ecommerce world, we tend to think of anything above a 3% conversion rate as something [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/">[Case Study] How to Easily Boost Conversion Rates with Personalization</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-style:italic">In today’s post, PrestaShop partner Nosto explains how Planet Fitness increased conversions using personalization.</span></p>
<p>Did you know that for every $92 spent on acquiring visitors, less than $1 is spent on converting them into customers?</p>
<p>The truth is, in the ecommerce world, we tend to think of anything above a 3% conversion rate as something to be happy about, but in a brick and mortar store this would be seen as catastrophic.<br />
<span id="more-20093"></span><br />
On average retailers are now spending 90% of their marketing budgets driving traffic to their stores, whether through SEO, PPC, affiliate marketing or social media channels. But what happens when the visitors you’ve spent so much of your precious budget acquiring get to your store? For most online shops &#8211; nothing. All visitors see exactly the same items regardless of their location, preferences or previous shopping behavior. They’re not treated as individuals with unique wants and needs.</p>
<p>Imagine this in the real world -it’s one thing to not want a pushy salesperson breathing down your neck while you browse, but what if that salesperson ignored you completely? The answer, quite rightly, is that you’re going to take your business elsewhere.</p>
<p>But this needn’t be the case. The ability to gather and utilize increasing amounts of data on customer behavior has allowed brands to start strengthening relationships with customers in a number of ways, with one of the most exciting and successful being personalization, a technology that has only recently become accessible to SME retailers.</p>
<p>And there are already a number of success stories. Planet Fitness, market leader for professionals in the fitness industry, is just one example of an innovative company that has turned to personalization to boost sales.</p>
<p>And boost sales it did! Since introducing personalized recommendations to their online store they have seen a whopping 68% increase in conversion, a 12% increase in average order value, and 70% more time spent on their site &#8212; all while keeping the end customer at the heart of the business.</p>
<p>So, how can you emulate this success in your business?</p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li>Add a top list to your front page to display the items from your store which were most popular in the previous week. Not only does this allow you to showcase the hottest items in your selection right now (capitalizing on current trends) but it also inspires your customers to browse further in your store and buy more of your fantastic stock! When Planet Fitness added this feature it started generating a impressive 6.1% conversion rate…</li>
<li>It’s an understatement to say that we lead busy lives, and the same is true for your customers. Save them the arduous task of trawling through page after page of items by putting best-seller lists on your site’s category pages as well; this enhances their browsing experience by showcasing a glimpse of the selection in each category. For Fitness Planet adding this feature and then some has increased the time spent on the site by 70% and the number of items browsed by 96%.</li>
<li>A customer’s browsing history is a great indicator of what they might be looking for. Add browsing history recommendations to your category pages to allow easy and visualized back and forth browsing. Not only will this tempt customers with relevant items but it will also allow them to reconsider pieces before heading for the checkout. Add this feature to the search page as well and they will have no excuse to forget what they were looking for!</li>
<li>Don’t trip on the last hurdle &#8211; just because someone is on the cart page doesn’t mean they aren’t open to buying more great stuff if you have it. Add cart recommendations to the cart page to encourage a last-minute purchase. This works by displaying items with the highest relevancy to the ones in already in the cart. Planet Fitness saw this feature work to great effect,  generating a conversion rate of 7.3%</li>
</ul>
<p>In short, personalization allows retailers to meet each customer’s needs and wants faster and more efficiently than ever before. Offering customers the most relevant content at all points throughout the buying journey increases customer satisfaction and loyalty as well as increasing conversion and boosting sales. What’s not to like?</p>
<p>The Nosto module ‘Personalization for PrestaShop’ is already pre-installed and ready for use in the PrestaShop solution.</p>
<p><a href="http://support.nosto.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Planet-Fitness-EN-WEB3.pdf" target="_blank">If you want to see personalization in practice why not have a more in-depth look at how PrestaShop’s partner Nosto worked with Planet Fitness</a>?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/">[Case Study] How to Easily Boost Conversion Rates with Personalization</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 reasons to stop by booth #445 at IRCE in Chicago !</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 15:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20087</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop is once again attending IRCE in Chicago&#8211;and we’ve got news for you! Join us at booth #445 to find out more. In the meantime, here are 3 great reasons e-merchants, entrepreneurs and brick-and-mortar store owners, developers web agencies and industry partners should stop by the PrestaShop booth starting June 2nd: 1. Our stand is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/">3 reasons to stop by booth #445 at IRCE in Chicago !</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop is once again attending IRCE in Chicago&#8211;and we’ve got news for you! Join us at booth <strong>#445</strong> to find out more. </p>
<p>In the meantime, here are 3 great reasons e-merchants, entrepreneurs and brick-and-mortar store owners, developers web agencies and industry partners should stop by the PrestaShop booth starting June 2nd:<br />
<span id="more-20087"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#0073de">1. Our stand is an interactive center for e-shop creation.</h2>
<p>Visitors will be able to see live demos of  PrestaShop Cloud, the hosted version of PrestaShop Download, launched in early January. With PrestaShop Cloud, merchants are able to create online stores for free and in a matter of minutes: the software is free, the hosting is free and there’s no commission. We’ve made ecommerce available to anyone, anywhere! <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en">Visit our site for more information</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color:#0073de">2. Discover our new look.</h2>
<p>On June 11th PrestaShop will unveil its new brand identity. Drop by our totally redesigned stand for a sneak peak at the new logo. </p>
<h2 style="color:#0073de">3. 230 000 online stores around the world use PrestaShop&#8211;so can you.</h2>
<p>PrestaShop offers software localized for the US market and has developed relationships with key industry partners to do so. For instance, PrestaShop just announced a shipping integration with <a href="http://www.stamps.com/" target="_blank">Stamps.com</a>® (NASDAQ: STMP), the leading online provider of USPS postage and shipping software, with nearly 500,000 customers. As a result of this integration, PrestaShop’s ecommerce merchants are able to import order data and print shipping labels for all USPS mail classes, domestic or international, track shipments, and receive discounts on shipping rates and package insurance.</p>
<p>The integration with Stamps.com, in addition to PrestaShop’s existing relationships with brands such as Convermax, Avalara, Brink&#8217;s, Authorize.Net, PayPal, PayU, ShippingEasy, Simplify Commerce by MasterCard and PriceWaiter underscores PrestaShop’s commitment to providing merchants with the support, tools and technology needed to successfully execute an online retail store and provide top-notch customer service.</p>
<p>Don’t wait&#8211;IRCE ends in 3 days! Drop by and see us at stand <strong>#445</strong> where our ecommerce experts are ready to answer your questions. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/">3 reasons to stop by booth #445 at IRCE in Chicago !</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating community at PrestaShop Day</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 08:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20082</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Here at PrestaShop, we’re getting really excited about the biggest event of our year: PrestaShop Day! We’ve reserved a beautiful and emblematic location in central Paris and selected a great line up of speakers, but what we’re really looking forward to is welcoming our community. PrestaShop has been invested in an open source, collaborative business [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/">Celebrating community at PrestaShop Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here at PrestaShop, we’re getting really excited about the biggest event of our year: PrestaShop Day! We’ve reserved a beautiful and emblematic location in central Paris and selected a great line up of speakers, but what we’re really looking forward to is welcoming our community. </p>
<p>PrestaShop has been invested in an open source, collaborative business model since we opened our doors in 2007. Our continued evolution and success is due in large part to the 800,000 strong community that contributes non-stop to building new businesses, tweaking code and developing new modules for merchants in markets around the world.<br />
<span id="more-20082"></span><br />
To thank you, the merchants, developers and web agencies that keep us moving forward, we’re proud to present a day devoted to helping you be even better at what you do. We’ve invited visionary leaders from e-commerce, web and open source to share their expertise, and organized workshops and conferences to help you go further in crucial areas like client acquisition, marketing and selling online. We’re also thrilled to be able to present the new PrestaShop branding, which we think you’re going to love. </p>
<p>We’ve always believed in open source and in our community. PrestaShop Day is our chance to give back to you. We hope you’ll join us on June 11th in Paris! </p>
<p>Register for free on the <a href="http://www.prestashopday.com/en/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Day</a> website with the code SoColissimoPSDAY !</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/">Celebrating community at PrestaShop Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maptiteculotte.com: an original concept that became a success story</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 13:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camille Sila]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20072</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Lingerie-lover Charline Goutal is an entrepreneur to the core who quickly identified something missing in her favorite sector. &#8220;I was looking for lingerie that I wanted to wear every day, but all I could find was a limited selection of classic little cotton panties, and they weren&#8217;t exactly aesthetically pleasing.&#8221; And so the idea for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/">Maptiteculotte.com: an original concept that became a success story</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lingerie-lover Charline Goutal is an entrepreneur to the core who quickly identified something missing in her favorite sector. &#8220;I was looking for lingerie that I wanted to wear every day, but all I could find was a limited selection of classic little cotton panties, and they weren&#8217;t exactly aesthetically pleasing.&#8221; And so the idea for Maptiteculotte.com was born: offer quality items that are comfortable to wear every day, with an original style that combines personality with a sense of humour. Brand identity with a smile: now that&#8217;s a good idea!<br />
<span id="more-20072"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#2c2c2c">Always in good company with PrestaShop.</h2>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">The Issue</h4>
<p>Finding the right partners to start a project is not always easy—Charline learned this the hard way. Following some less than great advice, she launched the first version of her site using a platform that was completely unsuited to her needs, which meant the whole site needed to be redone. Luckily, Charline applied for and received funding from French Tech, which allowed her to rebuild her shop using a new solution. </p>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">Challenges</h4>
<p>Charline no longer had room for error: she needed an e-commerce solution that would facilitate the day-to-day management of her shop without limiting her plans for growth. Her concept depended on creating a powerful brand universe, so she also needed to find a web agency that could bring her shop alive in the way she had imagined it. </p>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">The result:</h4>
<p>&#8220;In the end, the recipe for success is knowing how to surround yourself with the right people. That means choosing a powerful e-commerce solution like PrestaShop, as well as having the support of a skilled and attentive associate, web agency, or freelancer. I chose to work with NewQuest, a PrestaShop partner agency that is well-known in the world of e-commerce.  Today, I&#8217;m proud of my shop, and I appreciate how easy PrestaShop is to use on an everyday basis, as well as the features that meet my current needs and future plans.&#8221;   </p>
<h2 style="color:#2c2c2c">PrestaShop: an ally to meet business needs</h2>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">The Issue</h4>
<p>Even before launching, Maptiteculotte.com had a small community on social networks that helped bring in the first orders fairly quickly. But a good beginning is not enough to guarantee a bright future: building customer loyalty and attracting new customers is vital to sustainable success.  </p>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">Challenges</h4>
<p>The goal was for Charline&#8217;s new store to help her apply all the best practices of e-commerce and implement the right marketing actions to create a unique experience for her customers. </p>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">The Result</h4>
<p>&#8220;Since migrating to PrestaShop, we noticed a clear increase in our sales thanks to a more complete store and a truly optimized purchasing funnel. We also appreciate being able to expand our store quickly with the modules available on PrestaShop Addons [the PrestaShop marketplace]. For example the Gift Card module lets us offer a product that many of our customers have requested.&#8221;   </p>
<h2 style="color:#2c2c2c">The Last Word</h2>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">Advice for future merchants</h4>
<p>&#8220;You have to try to bring something fresh to your market, with an original concept that sets you apart. And you have to make sure you follow e-commerce best practices.&#8221;<br />
Want to create your own online store like Maptiteculotte.com? Get started today with <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en">PrestaShop Cloud</a>, the hosted version of our e-commerce software.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/">Maptiteculotte.com: an original concept that became a success story</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Key Steps For A Successful Email Campaign</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 13:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20042</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>First things first: stop thinking about email campaigns as relics of a bygone era that are falling into decline. Only poorly designed and badly prepared campaigns end up like this. These days, up to 10% of e-commerce transactions come entirely from email campaigns, which means that any company that wants to sell online has to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/">10 Key Steps For A Successful Email Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First things first: stop thinking about email campaigns as relics of a bygone era that are falling into decline. Only poorly designed and badly prepared campaigns end up like this.</p>
<p>These days, up to 10% of e-commerce transactions come entirely from email campaigns, which means that any company that wants to sell online has to understand and integrate email best practices.</p>
<p>A good campaign still has a healthy future if it has a simple layout, is quick to send, and has instant results that you can analyze. Here are 10 tips to ensure effective, sustainable campaigns.<br />
<span id="more-20042"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Targeting" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/ciblage.png" width="50" height="50" /> Targeting</h2>
<p>This is what your entire campaign will be based on. Start by ensuring the quality of your database: make sure that you have legally obtained the addresses, that there are no spelling errors, and that you have the first and last names of your addressees. Don&#8217;t even think about using databases that you purchased, or even worse, obtained illegitimately on the Internet. First, it&#8217;s illegal. But also, nobody reads an email that they have not voluntarily opted in to receive.</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;ve finished this stage, targeting can really begin. You have to segment your database by type of contact: new prospects, active customers, old customers, etc. You&#8217;d certainly never send a welcome newsletter to an existing customer, just like you wouldn&#8217;t try to build customer loyalty with someone who&#8217;s never made a purchase!</p>
<p>It might seem obvious, but you should realize that 51% of customers unsubscribe because they get emails that are not adapted to their needs. Get to know your customers: their wants, their passions, and their needs. A qualified database leads to satisfied customers.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Responsive email" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/responsivemail.png" width="50" height="50" /> Responsive email</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s 2015: the future is now. Your contacts check their email more and more frequently on their smartphones. Return Path estimates that smartphones are used to open 50% of emails worldwide&#8230; a figure that can&#8217;t be ignored.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why you must make sure that your email campaign is easy to read on mobile devices. This means using &#8220;responsive design.&#8221;</p>
<p>A responsive email campaign must not be too long or complicated. If your reader has to scroll for 3 minutes while squinting to read text that is too dense and too long, you can be sure that all they will see is the unsubscribe button.</p>
<p>Our advice for a successful responsive email campaign:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Simplify your email by using adjustable blocks</li>
<li>Remove excessive items such as polls or aesthetic elements</li>
<li>Adjust your menus</li>
<li>Avoid putting photos and text side-by-side: place them one on top of another</li>
<li>Make sure your copy is easy to read</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t try to make it look identical to your desktop version</li>
<li><strong>TEST BEFORE YOU SEND</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Be sure to choose an email campaign solution that makes it incredibly simple to create a perfectly responsive newsletter. With our solution, Sarbacane Desktop, you can create a professional newsletter all by yourself! It&#8217;s very simple, and automatically responsive.</p>
<p>Download <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/19001-sarbacanedesktop.html" target="_blank">Sarbarcane Desktop</a> for free.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Responsive email" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/objetaccrocheur.png" width="50" height="50" /> A catchy subject</h2>
<p>You&#8217;re now off to a great start for a successful email campaign. But readers still have to decide whether or not to open it. There&#8217;s nothing quite like a convincing subject to encourage them to do so. It&#8217;s THE factor that determines if your email will be opened, and therefore how effective the campaign will be.</p>
<p>The subject must be short, intriguing, and concise. Aim for originality. Boldness and relevance are the key factors. Avoid far too generic terms like &#8220;free,&#8221; &#8220;win,&#8221; &#8220;sale,&#8221; &#8220;click now,&#8221; and so on.</p>
<p>Another point before the opening: the preheader. It should summarize your essential message in one sentence.</p>
<p>Place the usual &#8220;<span>If this message does not display correctly, click here</span>&#8221; <strong>after it</strong>, because the first sentence is what your addressee will see in their email previews.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="A coherent structure" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/structure.png" width="50" height="50" /> A coherent structure</h2>
<p>So now they&#8217;ve opened your email&#8230; but it&#8217;s not over yet. It&#8217;s time to talk about the most important thing: structure.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>The header: this includes the famous call to action, your company&#8217;s logo, and a slogan.</li>
<li>The body: the main topic is introduced here, with the essential information right away. Balance text and images (about 50/50), and don&#8217;t overdo it.</li>
<li>You want useful links that are customized, but not too many of them, and adapted landing pages.</li>
<li>Your phone numbers, email address and physical address should be here, and they should be clickable to save time (particularly on smartphones).</li>
<li>Share buttons for social networks</li>
<li>Elements of credibility</li>
<li>Obligatory unsubscribe link</li>
</ul>
<p>We&#8217;ll revisit some of these points in greater detail.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="A coherent structure" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/contenu.png" width="50" height="50" /> Quality content</h2>
<p>Your email campaign must have a clear objective that you will focus on no matter what. Try to showcase your subject, a promotion, or a special offer. Organize and rank your newsletter according to how important the information is. Each element should be carefully positioned: leave nothing to chance. Everything depends on your topic!</p>
<p>The first thing you need to do is prepare well in advance. Don&#8217;t write your email at the last minute: it will show! Preparing a schedule will also help you keep your mailings consistent and regular.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Call to action" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/cta.png" width="50" height="50" /> Call to action</h2>
<p>The &#8220;call to action&#8221; is the engaging appeal that you must at all costs place on an image, a banner, or a button containing a direct link that will lead to the product you wish to sell. Its wording should invite readers to interact with your company. Common examples include &#8220;Subscribe,&#8221; &#8220;Learn more,&#8221; &#8220;Get this deal,&#8221; and &#8220;Download our app.&#8221;</p>
<p>They let you clearly feature a link and encourage a click by using an action word.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Dedicated landing pages" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/landingpage.png" width="50" height="50" /> Dedicated landing pages</h2>
<p>When customers click on a link, it is always preferable that they be redirected to a landing page that welcomes them warmly to your site, and clearly indicates the process they should follow to get to where they want to go. Ideally you&#8217;ll create a dedicated landing page for each new campaign.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Credibility" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/reassurance.png" width="50" height="50" /> Credibility</h2>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget your objective: selling. If users are going to make a purchase on your site, they need be sure they&#8217;re not going to be ripped off. You must do everything you can to earn their trust so that they complete their transaction.</p>
<p>This is &#8220;credibility.&#8221; Add phrases to your newsletter like &#8220;Satisfaction guaranteed, or your money back,&#8221; along with indicators of authenticity such as labels. You can also display positive reviews, reassure users that their transactions on your site are secure, or offer them help with a contact form or a direct phone number, among other things. Reassure them as much as possible!</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Social links" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/liensocial.png" width="50" height="50" /> Social links</h2>
<p>Social networks are not the end of email campaigns – quite the contrary! Their benefits can be crucial for certain businesses. If you think they are indispensable for your company, add buttons that link to your Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Pinterest, Instagram, and other accounts, depending on which networks are useful to you, and on your campaign&#8217;s targets.<br />
This technique has several benefits, including:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Converting your email contacts into fans</li>
<li>Promoting the viral nature of your campaigns using sharing</li>
<li>Managing your community and ensuring you project a modern image</li>
<li>Reaching new targets and making your brand known</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Unsubscription" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/desabonnement.png" width="50" height="50" /> Unsubscription</h2>
<p>We&#8217;d never wish it upon you, but we want you to be prepared: it is crucial that you add an unsubscribe link to the bottom of your emails. It shouldn&#8217;t be too visible, but it shouldn&#8217;t be hidden either! If you don&#8217;t have an unsubscribe link, this can lead to users flagging your emails as SPAM, which will hurt your image.</p>
<p>To conclude this article, we can&#8217;t encourage you enough to TEST your newsletters before sending them. Do an A/B test if necessary to compare two versions of an email campaign, and see which one is more effective. Don&#8217;t forget that once you&#8217;ve sent it, it&#8217;s too late!</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="The Sarbacane advantage" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/plus.png" width="50" height="50" /> The Sarbacane advantage</h2>
<p>With <strong>Sarbacane Desktop</strong>, the leading French provider of email campaign solutions, you can meet all of these objectives easily and simply. Equipped with a <strong>Prestashop module that&#8217;s available directly in your back office</strong>, Sarbacane is a solution designed for e-commerce, with segmentation of your lists, advanced statistical analyses, and hundreds of free responsive templates. Sarbacane offers you a wide range of possibilities to help you create ideal email campaigns.</p>
<p>Download <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/19001-sarbacanedesktop.html" target="_blank">Sarbarcane Desktop</a> for free.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/">10 Key Steps For A Successful Email Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 reasons USPS is great for eCommerce shipping</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 15:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20064</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When most companies need to ship packages, they usually turn to what they know &#8211; UPS or FedEx. These two carriers are the first choice for many companies because have built their reputation with great marketing and do a great job overall. However, there is an overlooked, often under-appreciated alternative that may be worth your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/">3 reasons USPS is great for eCommerce shipping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When most companies need to ship packages, they usually turn to what they know &#8211; UPS or FedEx.  These two carriers are the first choice for many companies because have built their reputation with great marketing and do a great job overall. However, there is an overlooked, often under-appreciated alternative that may be worth your consideration when making shipping decisions – The US Postal Service (USPS).<br />
<span id="more-20064"></span><br />
USPS has a wide range of products and services to meet every online shop’s needs – ranging from flat rate shipping to day-specific deliveries. They are a great option for online shops because they offer competitive pricing, have upfront fees, and faster delivery for the same price. </p>
<h2 style="color:#fc8114">1. Competitive Prices for Express Shipping</h2>
<p>USPS offers some of the best pricing in the industry. They can do so because of the volume of packages they transport on any given day. However, too many small business unwittingly pay two or even three times what USPS charges. This is especially true when online merchants need small packages delivered in 1 or 2 days.<br />
USPS’s Priority and Express Mail are two shipping options that feature day-specific delivery and are completely track-able. Before you pay for your next express shipping, check out USPS’s rates to ensure you’re not overpaying for these services.</p>
<h2 style="color:#fc8114">2. Upfront Costs, without Fees</h2>
<p>FedEx and UPS customers are all too familiar with their complex invoices at the end of each month. It’s not the case with USPS; the cost of shipping a package is upfront. The price you see is the price you pay.</p>
<p>For example, as a B2C online merchant, you generally ship to residential addresses. Did you know that both UPS and FedEx charge a residential delivery fee of approximately $3.50 for each package? In comparison, USPS does not. This is just one example of the fees that private shipping companies charge. Make sure you’re getting the best deal on your shipping fees.</p>
<h2 style="color:#fc8114">3. Faster Delivery for Comparable Prices</h2>
<p>Shipping packages using a ground service for delivery in 5-7 days?  These packages are transported via truck across the country. For both USPS Priority and Express Mail, your packages are flown to their destination and can be expected to arrive in 1-3 days.</p>
<p>The cost for the USPS Priority Service may initially seem higher than UPS or FedEx’s ground service, but when you add the residential delivery fee, in addition to the Ground Shipping fee, the cost difference may be $1.00 to $2.00 in favor of USPS.  Also consider the transit time difference of 1-3 days for USPS vs. 5-7 days for UPS or FedEx. You increase your customers’ satisfaction with the quicker deliveries that makes it worth the marginal cost. After all, who doesn’t like receiving packages earlier?</p>
<h2 style="color:#fc8114">In a Nutshell</h2>
<p>As with any business decision, knowledge is key. Although we love FedEx and USPS, it’s time to start considering the advantages of shipping with USPS. Not only do they offer comparable prices for similar services, they are getting increasing competitive in the different types of services they offer.</p>
<p>To make the best business decision for your online shop, you should be able to see all your options on one screen. With the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/shipping-logistics-delivery-prestashop-modules/18335-sellstrom.html" target="_blank">PrestaShop SGS Shipping Module</a>, access shipping fees from UPS, USPS and FedEx for the products in a PrestaShop Cart. For more details and the shipping options, <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/shipping-logistics-delivery-prestashop-modules/18335-sellstrom.html" target="_blank">download the module for free</a>. Get started today with a free 30-day trial. Enjoy access to shipping with multiple carriers and create shipping labels with just one click.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/">3 reasons USPS is great for eCommerce shipping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
