<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 14:00:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>PrestaShop launches a $1,000,000 Integration Fund for the Community</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaux Choplin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20101</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Since its creation in 2007, PrestaShop has helped thousands of merchants achieve success through their online stores. Over the years, many new features have been added to the open source software thanks to its unique ecosystem. The latest evolution is our Cloud version, which we were proud to release earlier this year. With no hosting [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/">PrestaShop launches a $1,000,000 Integration Fund for the Community</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since its creation in 2007, PrestaShop has helped thousands of merchants achieve success through their online stores. Over the years, many new features have been added to the open source software thanks to its unique ecosystem. The latest evolution is our Cloud version, which we were proud to release earlier this year. With no hosting fees, PrestaShop Cloud allows merchants anywhere to create a store in a single click.</p>
<p>Each innovation is inspired by our desire to simplify ecommerce and make it accessible to everyone across the world. The 800,000 members of our incredible community and our shared passion for ecommerce are what make it all possible. Our success is driven by our community via the PrestaShop Addons Marketplace. This year our contributors will earn over $5,000,000 selling their modules and themes on our marketplace!</p>
<p>We want every developer to be able to give the emerchants in his or her country the power to easily achieve ecommerce success. That’s why we’re thrilled to announce the launch of a <strong>$1,000,000 Integration Fund</strong> dedicated to our community and intended to reinforce the positive relationships with developers that have contributed to our shared success.<br />
<span id="more-20101"></span></p>
<h4 style="color:#df0064">$1,000,000 to invest in our global community </h4>
<p>Using this Fund, we hope to build a catalog of local modules so that every merchant, no matter where they are, has access to the basic features necessary to run a successful eCommerce activity in his or her country (payment modules, shipping modules, modules for local marketplace connection and modules to simplify administrative procedures).</p>
<h4 style="color:#df0064">How can you get involved?</h4>
<p>It’s simple. Whether you’re a new contributor or you’ve been with us for a while, just send us your idea for a local module. </p>
<p>If your idea and skills convince us to select your project, you’ll be eligible to receive funding to cover your development costs (this amount is determined on a case-by-case basis). Once your module is developed and online on PrestaShop Addons, you’ll receive this personalized funding, as well as 30% of the revenues on your module’s sales (until the PrestaShop’s total commission on your module  reaches the amount of the awarded funding), then 70% on all following sales. </p>
<p>&#8220;I first developed a shipping solution for my uncle’s e-shop that I now sell on Addons Marketplace. I ended up selling it almost 2,000 times”, says Emmanuel M, Addons contributor. Instead of taking on the costs of a custom-made development, merchants can buy modules on Addons Marketplace and benefit from high-volume availability, reducing costs by a factor of more than 20. For developers, the Addons Marketplace offers an incredible opportunity to significantly increase revenues. The Integration Fund was created to drive module development and foster positive relationships between community members and PrestaShop. </p>
<p>Do you have an idea for your local market? </p>
<p><a href="https://addons.prestashop.com/integration-fund" target="_blank">Pitch your idea and apply for the PrestaShop Integration Fund</a></p>
<p>Stay tuned on the Integration Fund thanks to the hashtag <strong>#1million4devs</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/">PrestaShop launches a $1,000,000 Integration Fund for the Community</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-launches-1000000-integration-fund-community/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>[Case Study] How to Easily Boost Conversion Rates with Personalization</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 12:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20093</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In today’s post, PrestaShop partner Nosto explains how Planet Fitness increased conversions using personalization. Did you know that for every $92 spent on acquiring visitors, less than $1 is spent on converting them into customers? The truth is, in the ecommerce world, we tend to think of anything above a 3% conversion rate as something [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/">[Case Study] How to Easily Boost Conversion Rates with Personalization</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-style:italic">In today’s post, PrestaShop partner Nosto explains how Planet Fitness increased conversions using personalization.</span></p>
<p>Did you know that for every $92 spent on acquiring visitors, less than $1 is spent on converting them into customers?</p>
<p>The truth is, in the ecommerce world, we tend to think of anything above a 3% conversion rate as something to be happy about, but in a brick and mortar store this would be seen as catastrophic.<br />
<span id="more-20093"></span><br />
On average retailers are now spending 90% of their marketing budgets driving traffic to their stores, whether through SEO, PPC, affiliate marketing or social media channels. But what happens when the visitors you’ve spent so much of your precious budget acquiring get to your store? For most online shops &#8211; nothing. All visitors see exactly the same items regardless of their location, preferences or previous shopping behavior. They’re not treated as individuals with unique wants and needs.</p>
<p>Imagine this in the real world -it’s one thing to not want a pushy salesperson breathing down your neck while you browse, but what if that salesperson ignored you completely? The answer, quite rightly, is that you’re going to take your business elsewhere.</p>
<p>But this needn’t be the case. The ability to gather and utilize increasing amounts of data on customer behavior has allowed brands to start strengthening relationships with customers in a number of ways, with one of the most exciting and successful being personalization, a technology that has only recently become accessible to SME retailers.</p>
<p>And there are already a number of success stories. Planet Fitness, market leader for professionals in the fitness industry, is just one example of an innovative company that has turned to personalization to boost sales.</p>
<p>And boost sales it did! Since introducing personalized recommendations to their online store they have seen a whopping 68% increase in conversion, a 12% increase in average order value, and 70% more time spent on their site &#8212; all while keeping the end customer at the heart of the business.</p>
<p>So, how can you emulate this success in your business?</p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li>Add a top list to your front page to display the items from your store which were most popular in the previous week. Not only does this allow you to showcase the hottest items in your selection right now (capitalizing on current trends) but it also inspires your customers to browse further in your store and buy more of your fantastic stock! When Planet Fitness added this feature it started generating a impressive 6.1% conversion rate…</li>
<li>It’s an understatement to say that we lead busy lives, and the same is true for your customers. Save them the arduous task of trawling through page after page of items by putting best-seller lists on your site’s category pages as well; this enhances their browsing experience by showcasing a glimpse of the selection in each category. For Fitness Planet adding this feature and then some has increased the time spent on the site by 70% and the number of items browsed by 96%.</li>
<li>A customer’s browsing history is a great indicator of what they might be looking for. Add browsing history recommendations to your category pages to allow easy and visualized back and forth browsing. Not only will this tempt customers with relevant items but it will also allow them to reconsider pieces before heading for the checkout. Add this feature to the search page as well and they will have no excuse to forget what they were looking for!</li>
<li>Don’t trip on the last hurdle &#8211; just because someone is on the cart page doesn’t mean they aren’t open to buying more great stuff if you have it. Add cart recommendations to the cart page to encourage a last-minute purchase. This works by displaying items with the highest relevancy to the ones in already in the cart. Planet Fitness saw this feature work to great effect,  generating a conversion rate of 7.3%</li>
</ul>
<p>In short, personalization allows retailers to meet each customer’s needs and wants faster and more efficiently than ever before. Offering customers the most relevant content at all points throughout the buying journey increases customer satisfaction and loyalty as well as increasing conversion and boosting sales. What’s not to like?</p>
<p>The Nosto module ‘Personalization for PrestaShop’ is already pre-installed and ready for use in the PrestaShop solution.</p>
<p><a href="http://support.nosto.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Planet-Fitness-EN-WEB3.pdf" target="_blank">If you want to see personalization in practice why not have a more in-depth look at how PrestaShop’s partner Nosto worked with Planet Fitness</a>?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/">[Case Study] How to Easily Boost Conversion Rates with Personalization</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/case-study-easily-boost-conversion-rates-personalization/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 reasons to stop by booth #445 at IRCE in Chicago !</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 15:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20087</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop is once again attending IRCE in Chicago&#8211;and we’ve got news for you! Join us at booth #445 to find out more. In the meantime, here are 3 great reasons e-merchants, entrepreneurs and brick-and-mortar store owners, developers web agencies and industry partners should stop by the PrestaShop booth starting June 2nd: 1. Our stand is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/">3 reasons to stop by booth #445 at IRCE in Chicago !</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PrestaShop is once again attending IRCE in Chicago&#8211;and we’ve got news for you! Join us at booth <strong>#445</strong> to find out more. </p>
<p>In the meantime, here are 3 great reasons e-merchants, entrepreneurs and brick-and-mortar store owners, developers web agencies and industry partners should stop by the PrestaShop booth starting June 2nd:<br />
<span id="more-20087"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#0073de">1. Our stand is an interactive center for e-shop creation.</h2>
<p>Visitors will be able to see live demos of  PrestaShop Cloud, the hosted version of PrestaShop Download, launched in early January. With PrestaShop Cloud, merchants are able to create online stores for free and in a matter of minutes: the software is free, the hosting is free and there’s no commission. We’ve made ecommerce available to anyone, anywhere! <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en">Visit our site for more information</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color:#0073de">2. Discover our new look.</h2>
<p>On June 11th PrestaShop will unveil its new brand identity. Drop by our totally redesigned stand for a sneak peak at the new logo. </p>
<h2 style="color:#0073de">3. 230 000 online stores around the world use PrestaShop&#8211;so can you.</h2>
<p>PrestaShop offers software localized for the US market and has developed relationships with key industry partners to do so. For instance, PrestaShop just announced a shipping integration with <a href="http://www.stamps.com/" target="_blank">Stamps.com</a>® (NASDAQ: STMP), the leading online provider of USPS postage and shipping software, with nearly 500,000 customers. As a result of this integration, PrestaShop’s ecommerce merchants are able to import order data and print shipping labels for all USPS mail classes, domestic or international, track shipments, and receive discounts on shipping rates and package insurance.</p>
<p>The integration with Stamps.com, in addition to PrestaShop’s existing relationships with brands such as Convermax, Avalara, Brink&#8217;s, Authorize.Net, PayPal, PayU, ShippingEasy, Simplify Commerce by MasterCard and PriceWaiter underscores PrestaShop’s commitment to providing merchants with the support, tools and technology needed to successfully execute an online retail store and provide top-notch customer service.</p>
<p>Don’t wait&#8211;IRCE ends in 3 days! Drop by and see us at stand <strong>#445</strong> where our ecommerce experts are ready to answer your questions. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/">3 reasons to stop by booth #445 at IRCE in Chicago !</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-stop-booth-445-irce-chicago/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating community at PrestaShop Day</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 08:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20082</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Here at PrestaShop, we’re getting really excited about the biggest event of our year: PrestaShop Day! We’ve reserved a beautiful and emblematic location in central Paris and selected a great line up of speakers, but what we’re really looking forward to is welcoming our community. PrestaShop has been invested in an open source, collaborative business [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/">Celebrating community at PrestaShop Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here at PrestaShop, we’re getting really excited about the biggest event of our year: PrestaShop Day! We’ve reserved a beautiful and emblematic location in central Paris and selected a great line up of speakers, but what we’re really looking forward to is welcoming our community. </p>
<p>PrestaShop has been invested in an open source, collaborative business model since we opened our doors in 2007. Our continued evolution and success is due in large part to the 800,000 strong community that contributes non-stop to building new businesses, tweaking code and developing new modules for merchants in markets around the world.<br />
<span id="more-20082"></span><br />
To thank you, the merchants, developers and web agencies that keep us moving forward, we’re proud to present a day devoted to helping you be even better at what you do. We’ve invited visionary leaders from e-commerce, web and open source to share their expertise, and organized workshops and conferences to help you go further in crucial areas like client acquisition, marketing and selling online. We’re also thrilled to be able to present the new PrestaShop branding, which we think you’re going to love. </p>
<p>We’ve always believed in open source and in our community. PrestaShop Day is our chance to give back to you. We hope you’ll join us on June 11th in Paris! </p>
<p>Register for free on the <a href="http://www.prestashopday.com/en/" target="_blank">PrestaShop Day</a> website with the code SoColissimoPSDAY !</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/">Celebrating community at PrestaShop Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/celebrating-community-prestashop-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maptiteculotte.com: an original concept that became a success story</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 13:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camille Sila]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20072</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Lingerie-lover Charline Goutal is an entrepreneur to the core who quickly identified something missing in her favorite sector. &#8220;I was looking for lingerie that I wanted to wear every day, but all I could find was a limited selection of classic little cotton panties, and they weren&#8217;t exactly aesthetically pleasing.&#8221; And so the idea for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/">Maptiteculotte.com: an original concept that became a success story</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lingerie-lover Charline Goutal is an entrepreneur to the core who quickly identified something missing in her favorite sector. &#8220;I was looking for lingerie that I wanted to wear every day, but all I could find was a limited selection of classic little cotton panties, and they weren&#8217;t exactly aesthetically pleasing.&#8221; And so the idea for Maptiteculotte.com was born: offer quality items that are comfortable to wear every day, with an original style that combines personality with a sense of humour. Brand identity with a smile: now that&#8217;s a good idea!<br />
<span id="more-20072"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#2c2c2c">Always in good company with PrestaShop.</h2>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">The Issue</h4>
<p>Finding the right partners to start a project is not always easy—Charline learned this the hard way. Following some less than great advice, she launched the first version of her site using a platform that was completely unsuited to her needs, which meant the whole site needed to be redone. Luckily, Charline applied for and received funding from French Tech, which allowed her to rebuild her shop using a new solution. </p>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">Challenges</h4>
<p>Charline no longer had room for error: she needed an e-commerce solution that would facilitate the day-to-day management of her shop without limiting her plans for growth. Her concept depended on creating a powerful brand universe, so she also needed to find a web agency that could bring her shop alive in the way she had imagined it. </p>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">The result:</h4>
<p>&#8220;In the end, the recipe for success is knowing how to surround yourself with the right people. That means choosing a powerful e-commerce solution like PrestaShop, as well as having the support of a skilled and attentive associate, web agency, or freelancer. I chose to work with NewQuest, a PrestaShop partner agency that is well-known in the world of e-commerce.  Today, I&#8217;m proud of my shop, and I appreciate how easy PrestaShop is to use on an everyday basis, as well as the features that meet my current needs and future plans.&#8221;   </p>
<h2 style="color:#2c2c2c">PrestaShop: an ally to meet business needs</h2>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">The Issue</h4>
<p>Even before launching, Maptiteculotte.com had a small community on social networks that helped bring in the first orders fairly quickly. But a good beginning is not enough to guarantee a bright future: building customer loyalty and attracting new customers is vital to sustainable success.  </p>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">Challenges</h4>
<p>The goal was for Charline&#8217;s new store to help her apply all the best practices of e-commerce and implement the right marketing actions to create a unique experience for her customers. </p>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">The Result</h4>
<p>&#8220;Since migrating to PrestaShop, we noticed a clear increase in our sales thanks to a more complete store and a truly optimized purchasing funnel. We also appreciate being able to expand our store quickly with the modules available on PrestaShop Addons [the PrestaShop marketplace]. For example the Gift Card module lets us offer a product that many of our customers have requested.&#8221;   </p>
<h2 style="color:#2c2c2c">The Last Word</h2>
<h4 style="color:#ea513f">Advice for future merchants</h4>
<p>&#8220;You have to try to bring something fresh to your market, with an original concept that sets you apart. And you have to make sure you follow e-commerce best practices.&#8221;<br />
Want to create your own online store like Maptiteculotte.com? Get started today with <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en">PrestaShop Cloud</a>, the hosted version of our e-commerce software.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/">Maptiteculotte.com: an original concept that became a success story</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/maptiteculotte-com-original-concept-became-success-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Key Steps For A Successful Email Campaign</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 13:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20042</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>First things first: stop thinking about email campaigns as relics of a bygone era that are falling into decline. Only poorly designed and badly prepared campaigns end up like this. These days, up to 10% of e-commerce transactions come entirely from email campaigns, which means that any company that wants to sell online has to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/">10 Key Steps For A Successful Email Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First things first: stop thinking about email campaigns as relics of a bygone era that are falling into decline. Only poorly designed and badly prepared campaigns end up like this.</p>
<p>These days, up to 10% of e-commerce transactions come entirely from email campaigns, which means that any company that wants to sell online has to understand and integrate email best practices.</p>
<p>A good campaign still has a healthy future if it has a simple layout, is quick to send, and has instant results that you can analyze. Here are 10 tips to ensure effective, sustainable campaigns.<br />
<span id="more-20042"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Targeting" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/ciblage.png" width="50" height="50" /> Targeting</h2>
<p>This is what your entire campaign will be based on. Start by ensuring the quality of your database: make sure that you have legally obtained the addresses, that there are no spelling errors, and that you have the first and last names of your addressees. Don&#8217;t even think about using databases that you purchased, or even worse, obtained illegitimately on the Internet. First, it&#8217;s illegal. But also, nobody reads an email that they have not voluntarily opted in to receive.</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;ve finished this stage, targeting can really begin. You have to segment your database by type of contact: new prospects, active customers, old customers, etc. You&#8217;d certainly never send a welcome newsletter to an existing customer, just like you wouldn&#8217;t try to build customer loyalty with someone who&#8217;s never made a purchase!</p>
<p>It might seem obvious, but you should realize that 51% of customers unsubscribe because they get emails that are not adapted to their needs. Get to know your customers: their wants, their passions, and their needs. A qualified database leads to satisfied customers.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Responsive email" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/responsivemail.png" width="50" height="50" /> Responsive email</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s 2015: the future is now. Your contacts check their email more and more frequently on their smartphones. Return Path estimates that smartphones are used to open 50% of emails worldwide&#8230; a figure that can&#8217;t be ignored.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why you must make sure that your email campaign is easy to read on mobile devices. This means using &#8220;responsive design.&#8221;</p>
<p>A responsive email campaign must not be too long or complicated. If your reader has to scroll for 3 minutes while squinting to read text that is too dense and too long, you can be sure that all they will see is the unsubscribe button.</p>
<p>Our advice for a successful responsive email campaign:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Simplify your email by using adjustable blocks</li>
<li>Remove excessive items such as polls or aesthetic elements</li>
<li>Adjust your menus</li>
<li>Avoid putting photos and text side-by-side: place them one on top of another</li>
<li>Make sure your copy is easy to read</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t try to make it look identical to your desktop version</li>
<li><strong>TEST BEFORE YOU SEND</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Be sure to choose an email campaign solution that makes it incredibly simple to create a perfectly responsive newsletter. With our solution, Sarbacane Desktop, you can create a professional newsletter all by yourself! It&#8217;s very simple, and automatically responsive.</p>
<p>Download <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/19001-sarbacanedesktop.html" target="_blank">Sarbarcane Desktop</a> for free.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Responsive email" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/objetaccrocheur.png" width="50" height="50" /> A catchy subject</h2>
<p>You&#8217;re now off to a great start for a successful email campaign. But readers still have to decide whether or not to open it. There&#8217;s nothing quite like a convincing subject to encourage them to do so. It&#8217;s THE factor that determines if your email will be opened, and therefore how effective the campaign will be.</p>
<p>The subject must be short, intriguing, and concise. Aim for originality. Boldness and relevance are the key factors. Avoid far too generic terms like &#8220;free,&#8221; &#8220;win,&#8221; &#8220;sale,&#8221; &#8220;click now,&#8221; and so on.</p>
<p>Another point before the opening: the preheader. It should summarize your essential message in one sentence.</p>
<p>Place the usual &#8220;<span>If this message does not display correctly, click here</span>&#8221; <strong>after it</strong>, because the first sentence is what your addressee will see in their email previews.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="A coherent structure" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/structure.png" width="50" height="50" /> A coherent structure</h2>
<p>So now they&#8217;ve opened your email&#8230; but it&#8217;s not over yet. It&#8217;s time to talk about the most important thing: structure.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>The header: this includes the famous call to action, your company&#8217;s logo, and a slogan.</li>
<li>The body: the main topic is introduced here, with the essential information right away. Balance text and images (about 50/50), and don&#8217;t overdo it.</li>
<li>You want useful links that are customized, but not too many of them, and adapted landing pages.</li>
<li>Your phone numbers, email address and physical address should be here, and they should be clickable to save time (particularly on smartphones).</li>
<li>Share buttons for social networks</li>
<li>Elements of credibility</li>
<li>Obligatory unsubscribe link</li>
</ul>
<p>We&#8217;ll revisit some of these points in greater detail.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="A coherent structure" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/contenu.png" width="50" height="50" /> Quality content</h2>
<p>Your email campaign must have a clear objective that you will focus on no matter what. Try to showcase your subject, a promotion, or a special offer. Organize and rank your newsletter according to how important the information is. Each element should be carefully positioned: leave nothing to chance. Everything depends on your topic!</p>
<p>The first thing you need to do is prepare well in advance. Don&#8217;t write your email at the last minute: it will show! Preparing a schedule will also help you keep your mailings consistent and regular.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Call to action" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/cta.png" width="50" height="50" /> Call to action</h2>
<p>The &#8220;call to action&#8221; is the engaging appeal that you must at all costs place on an image, a banner, or a button containing a direct link that will lead to the product you wish to sell. Its wording should invite readers to interact with your company. Common examples include &#8220;Subscribe,&#8221; &#8220;Learn more,&#8221; &#8220;Get this deal,&#8221; and &#8220;Download our app.&#8221;</p>
<p>They let you clearly feature a link and encourage a click by using an action word.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Dedicated landing pages" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/landingpage.png" width="50" height="50" /> Dedicated landing pages</h2>
<p>When customers click on a link, it is always preferable that they be redirected to a landing page that welcomes them warmly to your site, and clearly indicates the process they should follow to get to where they want to go. Ideally you&#8217;ll create a dedicated landing page for each new campaign.</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Credibility" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/reassurance.png" width="50" height="50" /> Credibility</h2>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget your objective: selling. If users are going to make a purchase on your site, they need be sure they&#8217;re not going to be ripped off. You must do everything you can to earn their trust so that they complete their transaction.</p>
<p>This is &#8220;credibility.&#8221; Add phrases to your newsletter like &#8220;Satisfaction guaranteed, or your money back,&#8221; along with indicators of authenticity such as labels. You can also display positive reviews, reassure users that their transactions on your site are secure, or offer them help with a contact form or a direct phone number, among other things. Reassure them as much as possible!</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Social links" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/liensocial.png" width="50" height="50" /> Social links</h2>
<p>Social networks are not the end of email campaigns – quite the contrary! Their benefits can be crucial for certain businesses. If you think they are indispensable for your company, add buttons that link to your Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Pinterest, Instagram, and other accounts, depending on which networks are useful to you, and on your campaign&#8217;s targets.<br />
This technique has several benefits, including:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Converting your email contacts into fans</li>
<li>Promoting the viral nature of your campaigns using sharing</li>
<li>Managing your community and ensuring you project a modern image</li>
<li>Reaching new targets and making your brand known</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Unsubscription" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/desabonnement.png" width="50" height="50" /> Unsubscription</h2>
<p>We&#8217;d never wish it upon you, but we want you to be prepared: it is crucial that you add an unsubscribe link to the bottom of your emails. It shouldn&#8217;t be too visible, but it shouldn&#8217;t be hidden either! If you don&#8217;t have an unsubscribe link, this can lead to users flagging your emails as SPAM, which will hurt your image.</p>
<p>To conclude this article, we can&#8217;t encourage you enough to TEST your newsletters before sending them. Do an A/B test if necessary to compare two versions of an email campaign, and see which one is more effective. Don&#8217;t forget that once you&#8217;ve sent it, it&#8217;s too late!</p>
<h2 style="color: #d15a51"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="The Sarbacane advantage" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/plus.png" width="50" height="50" /> The Sarbacane advantage</h2>
<p>With <strong>Sarbacane Desktop</strong>, the leading French provider of email campaign solutions, you can meet all of these objectives easily and simply. Equipped with a <strong>Prestashop module that&#8217;s available directly in your back office</strong>, Sarbacane is a solution designed for e-commerce, with segmentation of your lists, advanced statistical analyses, and hundreds of free responsive templates. Sarbacane offers you a wide range of possibilities to help you create ideal email campaigns.</p>
<p>Download <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/advertising-marketing-newsletter-modules/19001-sarbacanedesktop.html" target="_blank">Sarbarcane Desktop</a> for free.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/">10 Key Steps For A Successful Email Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 reasons USPS is great for eCommerce shipping</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 15:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20064</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When most companies need to ship packages, they usually turn to what they know &#8211; UPS or FedEx. These two carriers are the first choice for many companies because have built their reputation with great marketing and do a great job overall. However, there is an overlooked, often under-appreciated alternative that may be worth your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/">3 reasons USPS is great for eCommerce shipping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When most companies need to ship packages, they usually turn to what they know &#8211; UPS or FedEx.  These two carriers are the first choice for many companies because have built their reputation with great marketing and do a great job overall. However, there is an overlooked, often under-appreciated alternative that may be worth your consideration when making shipping decisions – The US Postal Service (USPS).<br />
<span id="more-20064"></span><br />
USPS has a wide range of products and services to meet every online shop’s needs – ranging from flat rate shipping to day-specific deliveries. They are a great option for online shops because they offer competitive pricing, have upfront fees, and faster delivery for the same price. </p>
<h2 style="color:#fc8114">1. Competitive Prices for Express Shipping</h2>
<p>USPS offers some of the best pricing in the industry. They can do so because of the volume of packages they transport on any given day. However, too many small business unwittingly pay two or even three times what USPS charges. This is especially true when online merchants need small packages delivered in 1 or 2 days.<br />
USPS’s Priority and Express Mail are two shipping options that feature day-specific delivery and are completely track-able. Before you pay for your next express shipping, check out USPS’s rates to ensure you’re not overpaying for these services.</p>
<h2 style="color:#fc8114">2. Upfront Costs, without Fees</h2>
<p>FedEx and UPS customers are all too familiar with their complex invoices at the end of each month. It’s not the case with USPS; the cost of shipping a package is upfront. The price you see is the price you pay.</p>
<p>For example, as a B2C online merchant, you generally ship to residential addresses. Did you know that both UPS and FedEx charge a residential delivery fee of approximately $3.50 for each package? In comparison, USPS does not. This is just one example of the fees that private shipping companies charge. Make sure you’re getting the best deal on your shipping fees.</p>
<h2 style="color:#fc8114">3. Faster Delivery for Comparable Prices</h2>
<p>Shipping packages using a ground service for delivery in 5-7 days?  These packages are transported via truck across the country. For both USPS Priority and Express Mail, your packages are flown to their destination and can be expected to arrive in 1-3 days.</p>
<p>The cost for the USPS Priority Service may initially seem higher than UPS or FedEx’s ground service, but when you add the residential delivery fee, in addition to the Ground Shipping fee, the cost difference may be $1.00 to $2.00 in favor of USPS.  Also consider the transit time difference of 1-3 days for USPS vs. 5-7 days for UPS or FedEx. You increase your customers’ satisfaction with the quicker deliveries that makes it worth the marginal cost. After all, who doesn’t like receiving packages earlier?</p>
<h2 style="color:#fc8114">In a Nutshell</h2>
<p>As with any business decision, knowledge is key. Although we love FedEx and USPS, it’s time to start considering the advantages of shipping with USPS. Not only do they offer comparable prices for similar services, they are getting increasing competitive in the different types of services they offer.</p>
<p>To make the best business decision for your online shop, you should be able to see all your options on one screen. With the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/shipping-logistics-delivery-prestashop-modules/18335-sellstrom.html" target="_blank">PrestaShop SGS Shipping Module</a>, access shipping fees from UPS, USPS and FedEx for the products in a PrestaShop Cart. For more details and the shipping options, <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/shipping-logistics-delivery-prestashop-modules/18335-sellstrom.html" target="_blank">download the module for free</a>. Get started today with a free 30-day trial. Enjoy access to shipping with multiple carriers and create shipping labels with just one click.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/">3 reasons USPS is great for eCommerce shipping</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-reasons-usps-is-great-for-ecommerce-shipping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Part 2: 7 customer fears and how to address them</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 08:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20010</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Shoppers are more discerning and demanding than ever thanks to their increased experience with online merchants&#8211;they’re also better at telling a fake from the real deal. In part 2 of our article on responding to customer fears, we address some of the more practical details that make shoppers hesitate to click through to checkout. 1. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/">Part 2: 7 customer fears and how to address them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shoppers are more discerning and demanding than ever  thanks to their increased experience with online merchants&#8211;they’re also better at telling a fake from the real deal.<br />
In part 2 of our article on responding to customer fears, we address some of the more practical details that make shoppers hesitate to click through to checkout.<br />
<span id="more-20010"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#252934">1. I can’t tell if I’ll like the product.</h2>
<p>The biggest drawback to online shopping is that you can’t pick up and touch products, turn them around in your hands or squint at the tiny details. However, you can do a lot to give your customers an accurate idea of what your products look like, and how they should be worn or used: use detailed, benefits-oriented product descriptions to answer any questions your customers might have, complemented by a variety of professional product photos taken from many different angles and zoom levels. Customer reviews can help buyers get a sense of the product as well. Also, think about including a way to show the size and scale of your products.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/eatingtools-1024x685.jpg" alt="eatingtools" width="700" height="468" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20012" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="https://www.eatingtools.com/" target="_blank">Eatingtools</a> does a beautiful job of illustrating products and describing how they might be used and in what situations.</span></p>
<h2 style="color:#252934">2. It might not get here on time—or ever.</h2>
<p>Partner up with trusted shipping suppliers who have a reputation for on-time delivery and clearly list them on your site. Give your customers the option to track packages, which is especially appreciated for time-sensitive orders. If you do fail to meet a shipping date or a package goes missing, use it as an opportunity to show your outstanding customer service by offering a replacement, a free gift or a significant discount on a future purchase. Make your shipping guarantees clear and easy to find.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/sweet_isabelle-1024x346.jpg" alt="sweet_isabelle" width="700" height="236" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20059" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="http://www.sweetisabelle.com/" target="_blank">Sweet Isabelle</a> lets customers know they’ll receive a tracking number as soon as their order is processed and shipped.</span></p>
<h2 style="color:#252934">3. If I don’t like, I’ll be stuck with it.</h2>
<p>A clear exchange and returns policy is the best remedy to problem this. If you can offer free shipping and returns, even better. But make sure your business can handle the added cost. Whatever policy you decide on, make sure it’s easy to understand and free from confusing jargon. Make it easy to find on your website. </p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/smallable-1024x715.jpg" alt="smallable" width="700" height="488" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20058" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="http://en.smallable.com/" target="_blank">Smallable’s</a> return policy is clear and complete.</span> </p>
<h2 style="color:#252934">4. There won’t be help if I need it. </h2>
<p>Customer service is a crucial component of an ecommerce business, maybe even more so in some way than at in a brick and mortar store. Because you have no face-to-face interaction with your customers, you have to be on top of problems from a distance. Depending on your budget and resources, you have a few different options for providing customer service. </p>
<p>Start with a simple <strong>FAQ</strong> that addresses the major (and yes, minor!) questions your customers may have about your products, your return policy, where and/or how your products are made, etc.<br />
If you have the resources, set up a customer service phone number. <strong>Online chat</strong> is another way to let your customers know you’re there for them. </p>
<p>Just be sure that you can follow through on your promise of customer service. </p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/maspatule-1024x570.png" alt="maspatule" width="700" height="389" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20014" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="http://www.maspatule.com/" target="_blank">MaSpatule.com</a> clearly indicates their customer service number and guarantees. Highlighting trusted shipping carriers and policies doesn’t hurt either.</span></p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/mamy_factory-1024x542.jpg" alt="mamy_factory" width="700" height="370" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20013" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="http://www.mamyfactory.com/en/" target="_blank">Mamy Factory</a>’s FAQ addresses questions about everything from working policies to materials used.</span></p>
<p>What other customer fears have you encountered? Let us know in the comments. Ready to start your ecommerce store? Visit <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/">PrestaShop</a> today! </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/">Part 2: 7 customer fears and how to address them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Simple Content Ideas for your About Us Page</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 08:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20037</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’re like most writers, you find that writing about yourself always seems impossible. No matter how long you stare at the blank page, simply thinking about writing content about yourself brings on a bout of writer’s block. It’s probably the reason the content for your About page has gone unfinished… until now. Today we’re [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/">6 Simple Content Ideas for your About Us Page</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’re like most writers, you find that writing about yourself always seems impossible. No matter how long you stare at the blank page, simply <span style="font-style:italic">thinking</span> about writing content about yourself brings on a bout of writer’s block. It’s probably the reason the content for your About page has gone unfinished… until now.</p>
<p>Today we’re sharing 6 simple content ideas to help you write your About Us page. If you’re lacking content, we’ll give you examples of what you can include. If you have too much content,  we’ve also got you covered with helpful questions to narrow it down. Whether you’re drafting your About Us page for the first time or simply updating it, read on for content ideas. You’ll be done in no time!<br />
<span id="more-20037"></span><br />
Before you even start coming up with content, you’ll need to <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">identify your audience</a>. If you’re running an online store, the About Us page should be directed towards customers who want to get to know your brand better. Keep this person in mind when you’re trying to figure out what you want to say.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">1. Company History</h2>
<p>The easiest place to start is by telling the story of how your shop came to be. This works well if your store has been open for a long time, even if you only recently started selling online. Start at the very beginning with the original founders and their reasons for starting the business. If your history starts to get too long, break it down into major milestones, then plot them on a timeline. Too many key events? Opt for milestones that interest the audience. For example, the date you joined the company may be interesting to you, but not to your audience.</p>
<p>If you’ve just launched your online business, don’t make up a company history. Nothing destroys trust faster than finding out a merchant lied. Rather than focusing on company history, you can choose to highlight your professional or personal life. Just be sure it adds to the story of your shop; otherwise, simply leave this section out.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">2. Share Your Passion</h2>
<p>Ask yourself, “What do I love about what I do?” and “Why?”</p>
<p>Deep down, you already know why you love what you do, this page is where you can share that with your customers. If you’re not quite sure why you sell the product you’ve selected, you’ll have to dig deep and think.  No matter what you love or why you love it, someone will be able to relate to it – as long as it’s authentic. In other words, if you’re still not sure about your answer, don’t make something up!</p>
<p>Sharing why you love what you do makes the shopping experience more personable for the customer. Customers are no longer making a purchase from just another website. They are making a purchase from someone who shares the same or a similar passion.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">3. Company Mission or Vision</h2>
<p>If your product or service is “revolutionary”, it is crucial that you include your company mission or vision. Use this opportunity to detail the problem that your product/service solves for your customer. Then share your expectations for the future of your company. Sharing your company vision helps sell potential customers on the idea behind a new product. If they weren’t completely sold on the product, this is your last opportunity to convert them.</p>
<p>If you sell regular products that aren’t new, listing your company mission or vision can also help define your shop’s overall goals. Again, make sure that if you include your mission, it must be relatable for the reader.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">4. List Partner Companies</h2>
<p>Work with some great companies? Show them off while you leverage their credibility – just be sure you have permission to use their logos. Here are examples of types of companies you can list:</p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li><strong>Investors</strong> – Any company or individual person who has given your company money</li>
<li><strong>Suppliers</strong> – The company you purchase products from</li>
<li><strong>Manufacturers</strong> – The company or brand that makes the product</li>
<li><strong>Retailers</strong> – A company that sells your products for you in a physical store</li>
<li><strong>“As seen in” publications</strong> – List any notable publications you’ve been featured in</li>
<li><strong>Non-profit organizations</strong> – Include any organizations you donate to or actively support</li>
</ul>
<p>Keep in mind that the focus of this page is to showcase your company. List only the companies that add to your ability to tell your shop’s story.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">5. Testimonials</h2>
<p>If you’re in the habit of brushing off compliments, it’s time to stop. Good customer testimonials can be very helpful in acquiring new customers. When someone offers a compliment, accept it graciously then (if it’s an appropriate time), ask for permission to publish their testimonial.</p>
<p>Don’t have testimonials available? It doesn’t hurt to ask for one. A great time to ask for a testimonial or referral is when you speak directly with a customer who is happy with your product or service. Keep in mind that testimonials don’t always have to come in the form of a traditional quote about your shop.</p>
<p>You can ask customers to like your social media pages to build a presence. External sources of praise for your shop helps you build credibility. Great testimonials reassure potential customers of your product or service.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">6. Images</h2>
<p>Use images to <span style="font-style:italic">show</span> customers what your company is all about. Whether you choose to focus on the staff that runs your website, the working space or company mascot, images can go a long way towards giving customers a firsthand look into your company. Be sure to include a caption for each picture so your audience clearly understands the message you want to get across with your images.</p>
<p>If you choose to use images as the main focus of your “About us” Page, remember that they shouldn’t detract from your company’s narrative. Use them strategically to not only highlight what’s important, but also to connect with the customer.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">Key Takeaways</h2>
<p>About Us pages can help companies connect with their customers. Use one or mix a few of these ideas to get started. Just be sure to keep these tips in mind:</p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li>Tell your story from the very beginning.</li>
<li>Put your passion front and center.</li>
<li>Share your hopes and dreams through your vision.</li>
<li>Leverage trust from partners.</li>
<li>Build trust with customer testimonials.</li>
<li>Use images to <span style="font-style:italic">illustrate</span> your story.</li>
</ul>
<p>Ready to update your online shop’s About Us page? What are you waiting for? From your PrestaShop back office, navigate to Preferences &gt; CMS &gt; About Us. Want to see some examples? Check out the <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/showcase">PrestaShop showcase</a>. Let us know your favorite examples in the comments below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/">6 Simple Content Ideas for your About Us Page</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Reasons your online store needs a Custom Domain Name</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 16:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve opened an online business with PrestaShop, then you know that we provide your store with a free domain name &#8211; [ShopName].PSwebstore.com. While this domain name will definitely get the job of pointing visitors to your shop done, you might want to consider giving your store its own custom domain name. To help you [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/">5 Reasons your online store needs a Custom Domain Name</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve opened an online business with PrestaShop, then you know that we provide your store with a free domain name &#8211; [ShopName].PSwebstore.com. While this domain name will definitely get the job of pointing visitors to your shop done, you might want to consider giving your store its own custom domain name. To help you decide if this is right for your business, check out our 5 reasons your online store needs a custom domain name.<br />
<span id="more-20004"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Looks Professional</h2>
<p>They say first impressions are lasting impressions. Before a customer lands on your website, they need to enter a web address. While [ShopName].PSwebstore.com may describe what your shop does, it doesn’t look professional. Just put yourself in your customers’ shoes. How much money would you spend on a shop hosted on the PSwebstore domain?</p>
<p>Having a custom domain name helps add credibility to your online store. Your homepage URL changes from [ShopName].PSwebstore.com to something along the lines of www. [ShopName].com. It’s hard to build trust in your shop, so it’s important to take advantage of this opportunity!</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Professional Email</h2>
<p>The second most important reason you need a custom domain name is the professional email address. Along with looking professional, it shows potential business partners that you’ve put time and effort into your shop. Now put yourself in your potential partners&#8217; shoes. Would you prefer to be emailing bob@shopname.com or BobShop@gmail.com?</p>
<p>Not convinced? Would you want to work with a person that emails you from contact@shopname.com or PrestaShopcontact@aol.com? It’s superficial, but having a professional email can go a long way in convincing businesses to work with you and more importantly – take you seriously as a small business owner.</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Search Engine Optimized</h2>
<p>You’ve probably heard lots about <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/find-the-right-seo-keywords-for-your-online-store/">the importance of SEO</a> for your online store. What you probably haven’t heard is that having a custom domain name can help your SEO. How? The first reason is that none of your customers will be searching for “PSwebstore”. The domain you choose will help you rank higher for those keywords than the domain name we’ve provided.</p>
<p>Second, the goal behind SEO is to help customers find your shop. A custom domain name helps you market your shop and brand, making it easier for you to stand out from your competitors and help customers find you. If you choose a relevant domain name with great keywords, it will be listed on every product page.</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Safeguard your brand</h2>
<p>It’s nearly impossible, or at least very expensive, to purchase a domain once it’s been taken by someone else. There’s a whole <a href="https://blog.asmallorange.com/2013/07/how-to-buy-a-domain-name-thats-already-taken/" target="_blank">process for trying to get the domain</a> you want, but it’s never guaranteed. So before you start building up your brand, make sure you’re promoting a brand with a domain name you’ll have access to.</p>
<p>Take, for example, my new favorite sunscreen brand, Sun Bum. When I typed in <a href="http://sunbum.com/" target="_blank">SunBum.com</a>, I was greeted with a parked domain. I automatically assumed that they didn’t have an online shop. What I later discovered was that they did have an online presence, but the URL is <a href="http://trustthebum.com/" target="_blank">http://trustthebum.com/</a>. Instead of the brand name, their URL is their slogan. Although some people (like me) figured it out eventually, consider all the customers who won’t. If you’re building a brand, claim your name. You’ll benefit from both the traffic you get, and you’ll be able to dictate the brand message.</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Relatively Cheap</h2>
<p>“Okay, these all seem like valid reasons, but how much will it cost me,” you ask. If you already have a PrestaShop store, you can purchase a domain for $16.66 (+ tax) a year. Think of it as trading in 4 coffeehouse drinks throughout the year! If you’re not convinced to spend that money, remember that you may have to pay a premium fee if someone else already owns that domain name. In 2013, the <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/martinzwilling/2013/01/14/get-a-domain-name-without-bankrupting-your-startup/" target="_blank">cost of a domain that was already reserved averaged around $5,000</a>.</p>
<p>If you’re on a tight budget, you can purchase the domain name first (without hosting). Once you start acquiring more funds then, then add the hosting and start building your online presence. (Or you can launch your <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/">PrestaShop Cloud store</a> with free hosting included!)</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">In a Nutshell</h2>
<p>Custom domain names offer an affordable way to look professional, optimize for search engines and, most importantly, protect your brand.</p>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>Have we convinced you that your online store needs a custom domain name? Start brainstorming ideas then check out this article about <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-name-for-your-online-store/">picking the right domain for your online shop</a>! Then log into your <a href="http://prestashop.com/">PrestaShop.com</a> account to register and purchase your domain name.</p>
<p>Not an online merchant yet? Get started selling online with PrestaShop’s free, hosted online shopping cart software!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/">5 Reasons your online store needs a Custom Domain Name</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
